Register of The Militant Photographic Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Domestic (United States) Scenes.
  - Right-wing groups and protests against
    - Ku Klux Klan (Box 15)
      - General (Folder 15: 1-2)
      - Greensboro, North Carolina, 1979 (Folder 15: 3)
    - LaRouche (Lyndon) group (Folder 15: 4)
    - Nazis (Folder 15: 5-6)
    - Vietnamese anti-communists
      - New York, 1983 (Folder 15: 7)
      - San Jose, California, 1985 (Folder 15: 8)
    - Terrorist acts
      - General (Folder 15: 9)
      - Against Socialist Workers Party
        - 1960s (Folder 15: 10)
        - 1970s (Folder 15: 11)
        - 1980s (Folder 15: 12)
  - Socialist Workers Party
    - Election campaigns
      - 1930s (Folder 15: 13)
      - 1940s (Folder 15: 14)
      - 1950s (Folder 15: 15)
      - 1960s (Folder 15: 16)
      - 1968 (Folder 15: 17-19)
      - 1970s (Folder 15: 20)
      - 1972 (Folder 15: 21-24)
      - 1976 (Folder 15: 25)
      - 1980 (Folder 15: 26)
      - 1984 (Folder 15: 27-28)
      - 1988 (Folder 15: 29)
      - 1990 (Folder 15: 30)
      - 1991 (Folder 15: 31)
      - 1992 (Box-folder 16: 1-3)
      - 1993 (Folder 16: 4)
      - 1994 (Folder 16: 5)
      - 1995 (Folder 16: 6-7)
      - 1996 (Folder 16: 8-9)
      - 1997 (Folder 16: 10)
      - 1998 (Folder 16: 11)
    - National conventions
      - General (Folder 16: 12)
      - 1969 (Folder 16: 13)
      - 1971 (Folder 16: 14)
      - 1975 (Folder 16: 15)
      - 1976 (Folder 16: 16)
      - 1977 (Folder 16: 17)
      - 1979 (Folder 16: 18)
      - 1981 (Folder 16: 19)
      - 1985 (Folder 16: 20)
      - 1988 (Folder 16: 21)
      - 1990 (Folder 16: 22)
      - 1991 (Folder 16: 23)
      - 1994 (Folder 16: 24)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 17: 1)
      - 1997 (Folder 17: 2)
    - Active workers conferences
      - 1970 (Folder 17: 3)
      - 1978 (Folder 17: 4)
      - 1980 (Folder 17: 5)
      - 1982 (Folder 17: 6)
      - 1986 (Folder 17: 7)
      - 1987 (Folder 17: 8)
      - 1989 (Folder 17: 9)
      - 1996 (Folder 17: 10)
      - 1998 (Folder 17: 11)
    - International socialist conferences
      - 1992 (Folder 17: 12)
      - 1997-1998 (Folder 17: 13)
    - Regional socialist educational conferences
      - 1994 (Folder 17: 14)
      - 1994-1995 (Folder 17: 15)
      - 1995-1996 (Folder 17: 16)
      - 1996 (Folder 17: 17)
      - 1998 (Folder 17: 18)
    - Memorial meetings
      - Cannon, James P., 1974 (Folder 17: 19)
      - Shaw, Ed, 1995 (Folder 17: 20)
      - Others, 1990s (Folder 17: 21)
    - Branch headquarters (Folder 17: 22)
    - Trade union fractions (Folder 17: 23)
    - Political Rights Defense Fund (lawsuit against Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1975-1981) (Folder 17: 24)
    - Individual members (Folder 17: 25)
  - Solidarity with peoples abroad (demonstrations and meetings in the U.S.) (Box 18)
    - Africa (general) (Folder 18: 1)
    - Angola (Folder 18: 2)
    - Asia (general) (Folder 18: 3)
    - Brazil
      - General (Folder 18: 4)
      - Movimiento de los Trabajadores sin Tierra tour, 1997 (Folder 18: 5)
    - Canada (Quebec) (Folder 18: 6)
    - Chile (Folder 18: 7)
    - China (Folder 18: 8)
    - Cuba
      - 1960 (Folder 18: 9)
      - Harlem (Fidel Castro visit), 1960 (Folder 18: 10)
      - Fair Play for Cuba Committee, 1960-1961 (Folder 18: 11)
      - Che Guevara memorial meeting, New York, 1967 (Folder 18: 12)
      - 1979 (Folder 18: 13)
      - General, 1970s to 1990s (Folder 18: 14-15)
      - General, 1980s and 1990s (Folder 18: 16)
      - Cuban youth tour, 1992 (Folder 18: 17)
      - Friendshipment to Cuba, 1993 (Folder 18: 18)
      - 1994 (Folder 18: 19)
      - Friendshipment to Cuba, 1994 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - Cuban youth tour (Pável Díaz Hernández), 1994 (Folder 19: 2)
      - 1995 (Folder 19: 3-4)
      - "Cuba Lives" International Youth Festival, 1995 (Folder 19: 5)
      - 1996 (Folder 19: 6-8)
      - 1997 (Folder 19: 9)
      - 1998 (Folder 19: 10)
      - 2000 (Folder 19: 11)
    - Dominican Republic (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - Ethiopia (Folder 20: 2)
    - Europe (general) (Folder 20: 3)
    - Greece, 1973 (Folder 20: 4)
    - Grenada (Folder 20: 5)
    - Haiti (Folder 20: 6-7)
    - Indonesia (Folder 20: 8)
    - Iran (Folder 20: 9)
    - Iraq (Folder 20: 10)
    - Ireland (Northern Ireland)
      - 1970s (Folder 20: 11)
      - 1980s (Folder 20: 12)
      - 1980s and 1990s (Folder 20: 13)
      - 1990s (Folder 20: 14)
      - Gerry Adams tour, 1990s (Folder 20: 15)
    - Korea (Folder 20: 16)
    - Latin America (general) (Folder 20: 17)
    - Palestine (Folder 20: 18)
    - Panama (Folder 20: 19)
    - Puerto Rico (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - Somalia (Folder 21: 2)
    - South Africa (anti-apartheid)
      - 1976-1983 (Folder 21: 3)
      - 1984-1985 (Folder 21: 4)
      - 1986-1993 (Folder 21: 5)
      - General, 1980s and 1990s (Folder 21: 6)
      - Nelson Mandela tour, 1990 (Folder 21: 7)
    - Soviet Union (dissidents) (Folder 21: 8)
    - Vietnam (Folder 21: 9)
  - Sports (Folder 21: 10)
  - Student protests
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1968 May-June (Folder 21: 11)
    - College campuses, 1960s and 1970s (Folder 21: 12-13)
    - Black/Afro-American students, 1960s and 1970s (Folder 21: 14)
    - Hispanic students, 1970s (Folder 21: 15)
    - New York School District 1, 1973 (Folder 21: 16)
    - High school students, 1970s and 1980s (Folder 21: 17)
    - Education cutback protests, 1970s to 1990s (Folder 21: 18)
    - General, 1980s and 1990s (Folder 21: 19)
  - Unemployed
    - Historical background (Folder 21: 20)
    - Lines, 1970s (Folder 21: 21)
    - Protests, 1970s and 1980s (Folder 21: 22)
  - Veterans' rights protests (Folder 21: 23)
  - Watergate scandal (Folder 21: 24)
  - Women's movement
    - Historical background (Folder 21: 25)
    - Women in industry (Folder 21: 26)
    - General—Protests, 1960s (Folder 21: 27)
    - Women's liberation protests, 1970s (Folder 21: 28)
    - Sexism in advertising, 1970s
      - Examples (Folder 21: 29)
      - Protests (Folder 21: 30)
    - Women's Equality Day, 1970 August 26 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Equal Rights Amendment
      - Demonstrations for
        - 1975-1979 (Folder 22: 2)
        - Richmond, 1980 January 13 (Folder 22: 3)
        - Chicago, 1980 May 10 (Folder 21: 4)
      - Demonstrations against, 1970s (Folder 22: 5)
    - Coalition of Labor Union Women, 1970s and 1980s (Folder 22: 6)
    - National Organization for Women, 1970s to 1990s (Folder 22: 7)
    - Forced sterilization protests, 1970s and 1980s (Folder 22: 8)
    - Abortion rights
      - Demonstrations for
        - 1970s (Folder 22: 9)
        - Women's National Abortion Action Coalition, 1970s (Folder 22: 10)
        - Edelin case, 1975 (Folder 22: 11)
        - 1980s (Folder 22: 12)
        - March for Women's Lives, Washington, D.C., 1986 March 9 (Folder 22: 13)
        - 1989 April (Folder 22: 14)
        - 1990s (Folder 22: 15)
        - 1991 (Folder 22: 16)
        - 1992 (Folder 22: 17)
        - 1993 (Box-folder 23: 1)
        - 1994 (Folder 23: 2)
        - 1995 (Folder 23: 3)
        - 1996 (Folder 23: 4)
        - 1997 (Folder 23: 5)
      - Demonstrations against
        - 1970s (Folder 23: 6)
        - 1980s (Folder 23: 7)
    - General
      - Protests, 1990s (Folder 23: 8)
      - Protests, 1997-1998 (Folder 23: 9)
  - Young Socialist Alliance/Young Socialists
    - 1958 (Folder 23: 10)
    - 1950s and 1960s (Folder 23: 11)
    - Conventions, 1960s to 1980s (Folder 23: 12)
    - General, 1970s to 1990s (Folder 23: 13)
    - National convention, 1991 (Folder 23: 14-15)
    - 1994-1995 (Folder 23: 16)
    - 1996 (Folder 23: 17)
    - 1997 (Folder 23: 18)
    - 1998 (Folder 23: 19)
  - Miscellaneous contact sheets (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
- International (Non-United States) Scenes.
  Photographic prints, contact sheets, and printed reproductions. Arranged alphabetically by country.
  - Africa—Maps (Folder 24: 3)
  - Africa, East—Maps (Folder 24: 4)
  - Africa, Southern—Maps (Folder 24: 5)
  - Albania (Folder 24: 6-7)
  - Algeria
    - General (Folder 24: 8)
    - War for independence (Folder 24: 9)
    - Mass rallies, Ben Bella regime (Folder 24: 10)
    - Individuals (Folder 24: 11)
  - Angola
    - General and maps (Folder 24: 12)
    - Independence struggle (Folder 24: 13)
    - Civil war (Folder 24: 14)
    - Individuals (Folder 24: 15)
  - Antigua (Folder 24: 16)
  - Argentina
    - General (Folder 24: 17)
    - Mass actions, 1960s and 1970s (Folder 24: 18)
    - Partido Socialista de los Trabajadores campaign (Juan Coral, José Paez), 1973 (Folder 24: 19)
    - Che Guevara conference, 1988 (Folder 24: 20)
    - Mass actions, 1990s (Folder 24: 21-22)
    - Individuals (Folder 24: 23)
  - Armenia (Folder 24: 24)
  - Australia (Box 25)
    - General (Folder 25: 1)
    - Aborigines (Folder 25: 2)
    - Labor struggles (Folder 25: 3)
    - Fourth Internationalists (Folder 25: 4)
    - Individuals (Folder 25: 5)
  - Austria—Historical background (Folder 25: 6)
  - Bangladesh—War for independence (Folder 25: 7)
  - Barbados (Folder 25: 8)
  - Belgium
    - Historical background (Folder 25: 9)
    - Protests (Folder 25: 10)
    - Individuals (Folder 25: 11)
  - Belize (Folder 25: 12)
  - Bolivia—Guerrilla campaign, 1966-1967 (Folder 25: 13)
  - Brazil
    - General (Folder 25: 14)
    - Movimiento de los Trabajadores sin Tierra, 1995 (Folder 25: 15)
    - Oil workers' strike, 1995 (Folder 25: 16)
    - Individuals (Folder 25: 17)
  - Bulgaria (Folder 25: 18)
  - Burkina Faso
    - Maps (Folder 25: 19)
    - General (Folder 25: 20)
    - Mass actions (Folder 25: 21)
    - Sankara, Thomas (Folder 25: 22)
    - Individuals (Folder 25: 23)
  - Burundi
    - Maps (Folder 25: 24)
    - General (Folder 25: 25)
  - Cambodia
    - Sihanouk, Prince (Folder 25: 26)
    - U.S. intervention, 1970-1975 (Folder 25: 27)
    - Refugees, 1979 (Folder 25: 28)
    - Heng Samrin regime, 1980s (Folder 25: 29)
    - Troops, 1980s (Folder 25: 30)
    - Chan Bun Han, 1982 (Folder 25: 31)
    - Individuals (Folder 25: 32)
  - Canada
    - Maps (Folder 25: 33)
    - Fourth Internationalists, 1950s to 1990s (Folder 25: 34)
    - Anti-Vietnam War protests, 1960s and 1970s (Folder 25: 35)
    - General (Box 26)
      - 1970-1995 (Folder 26: 1)
      - 1996-1998 (Folder 26: 2)
    - Labor protests and strikes
      - 1970s to 1990s (Folder 26: 3)
      - 1980s and 1990s (Folder 26: 4)
      - 1996-1998 (Folder 26: 5)
    - Quebec independence protests
      - 1970s and 1980s (Folder 26: 6)
      - 1990s (Folder 26: 7)
    - Abortion rights protests, 1980s and 1990s (Folder 26: 8)
    - Police brutality protests, 1980s and 1990s (Folder 26: 9)
    - Anti-racist protests, 1990s (Folder 26: 10)
    - Farm protests, 1990s (Folder 26: 11)
    - Immigration rights protests, 1990s (Folder 26: 12)
    - Indian/Native peoples protests, 1990s (Folder 26: 13)
    - Miscellany (Folder 26: 14)
    - Individuals (Folder 26: 15)
  - Caribbean region—Anti-Imperialist Organizations of the Caribbean and Central America conferences (Box-folder 27: 1-2)
  - Central African Republic—Maps (Folder 27: 3)
  - Chile
    - General (Folder 27: 4)
    - Historical background (Folder 27: 5)
    - Salvador Allende regime (Folder 27: 6-7)
    - Coup, 1973 (Folder 27: 8)
  - China
    - Historical background (Folder 27: 9)
    - Mao Zedong and Mao cult (Folder 27: 10)
    - Mao Zedong and foreign visitors (Folder 27: 11)
    - Chou En-lai (Folder 27: 12)
    - Lin Piao (Folder 27: 13)
    - General, post-Mao period (Folder 27: 14)
    - Protests, including Tiananmen Square incident (Folder 27: 15)
    - Women (Folder 27: 16)
    - United Nations Conference on Women, Beijing, 1995 (Folder 27: 17)
    - Individuals (Folder 27: 18)
  - Colombia (Folder 27: 19)
  - Congo (Zaire)
    - General (Folder 27: 20-21)
    - Foreign troops (Folder 27: 22)
    - Lumumba, Patrice (Folder 27: 23)
    - Mobutu, Joseph (Folder 27: 24)
    - Individuals (Folder 27: 25)
  - Costa Rica
    - General (Folder 27: 26)
    - Individuals (Folder 27: 27)
  - Cuba
    - Maps (Folder 27: 28)
    - Castro, Fidel
      - Pre-1959
        - Prints (Folder 27: 29)
        - Negatives (Folder 27: 30)
      - 1959 and 1960s (Folder 27: 31)
      - 1970s (Folder 27: 32)
      - 1980s (Folder 27: 33)
      - 1990s (Folder 27: 34)
    - Guevara, Che (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - Agriculture
      - 1959 and 1960s (Folder 28: 2)
      - 1970s (Folder 28: 3)
      - 1980s (Folder 28: 4)
      - 1990s (Folder 28: 5)
      - 1996 (Folder 28: 6)
    - Attacks on, 1959 and 1960s (Folder 28: 7)
    - Culture
      - 1959 and 1960s (Folder 28: 8)
      - 1970s (Folder 28: 9)
    - Factories and workers
      - 1959 and 1960s (Folder 28: 10)
      - 1980s (Folder 28: 11)
      - Minibrigades, 1980s (Folder 28: 12)
      - Venceremos brigade, 1989 (Folder 28: 13)
      - 1990s (Folder 28: 14)
      - Microbrigades, 1990s (Box-folder 29: 1)
    - Mass demonstrations
      - 1959 and 1960s (Folder 29: 2)
      - 1970s (Folder 29: 3)
      - 1980s (Folder 29: 4)
      - 1990s (Folder 29: 5)
    - Military
      - 1959 and 1960s (Folder 29: 6)
      - 1980s (Folder 29: 7)
      - 1990s (Folder 29: 8)
    - Posters and signs
      - 1959 and 1960s (Folder 29: 9)
      - 1970s (Folder 29: 10)
    - Religion, 1959 and 1960s (Folder 29: 11)
    - Youth, education and health care
      - 1959 and 1960s (Folder 29: 12)
      - 1970s (Folder 29: 13)
      - 1980s (Folder 29: 14-15)
    - Playa Giron (Bay of Pigs) and Cuban Missile Crisis, 1961-1962 (Folder 29: 16)
    - Organizacion Latinoamericana de Solidaridad conference, Havana, 1967 (Folder 29: 17)
    - General
      - 1970s (Folder 29: 18)
      - 1990s (Folder 29: 19)
      - 1994 (Folder 29: 20)
    - Conferences, 1980s (Box-folder 30: 1)
    - Emigrants to the U.S., 1980s (Folder 30: 2)
    - Internationalists, 1980s (Folder 30: 3)
    - Social conditions
      - 1980s (Folder 30: 4)
      - 1990s (Folder 30: 5)
      - 1996 (Folder 30: 6)
    - Women, 1980s (Folder 30: 7)
    - Partido Comunista and Union de Jovenes Comunistas congresses, 1986-1987 (Folder 30: 8)
    - Fabio Ochoa case, 1989 (Folder 30: 9)
    - International brigades, 1990s (Folder 30: 10)
    - Union de Jovenes Comunistas, 1990s (Folder 30: 11)
    - Haitian detainees, Guantanamo, 1992 (Folder 30: 12)
    - Library and Philosophers Conferences, Holguin, 1992-1993 (Folder 30: 13)
    - FMC conference, Havana, 1993 (Folder 30: 14)
    - Che Guevara conference, 1993 (Folder 30: 15)
    - Sao Paulo Forum, Havana, 1993 (Folder 30: 16)
    - Guantanamo, 1994 (Folder 30: 17)
    - Latin American and Caribbean Conference, Havana, 1994 (Folder 30: 18)
    - Philosophers Conference, University of Havana, 1994 (Folder 30: 19)
    - "Cuba Lives" International Youth Festival, Havana, 1995 (Folder 30: 20)
    - Central de Trabajadores congress and workers' meetings, 1996 (Box-folder 31: 1-2)
    - May Day, Havana, 1996 (Folder 31: 3)
    - Tricontinental Conference, Havana, 1997 (Folder 31: 4)
    - World Festival of Youth and Students, Havana, 1997 (Folder 31: 5)
    - Women's Conference, Havana, 1998 (Folder 31: 6)
    - Individuals
      - Historical background (Folder 31: 7)
      - 1950s and 1960s (Folder 31: 8)
      - 1970s (Folder 31: 9)
      - 1980s (Folder 31: 10)
      - 1990s (Folder 31: 11)
    - American visitors (Socialist Workers Party, Young Socialist Alliance/Young Socialists, Pathfinder Press, The Militant, etc.)
      - Farrell Dobbs tour, 1960 (Folder 31: 12)
      - Young Socialist Alliance tour, 1968-1969 (Folder 31: 13-14)
      - 1980s (Folder 31: 15)
      - General, 1996 (Folder 31: 16)
      - U.S.-Cuba Youth Exchange, 1996 (Folder 31: 17)
      - Young Socialists, 1996 (Folder 31: 18)
      - 1997 (Folder 31: 19)
      - Havana Book Fairs (Box 32)
        - 1996 (Folder 32: 1)
        - 1998 (Folder 32: 2)
  - Curaçao—Individuals (Folder 32: 3)
  - Cyprus
    - General (Folder 32: 4)
    - War, 1974 (Folder 32: 5)
    - International Youth Forum for Peace in the Middle East, 1991 (Folder 32: 6)
  - Czechoslovakia
    - General (Folder 32: 7-8)
    - Soviet intervention, 1968 (Folder 32: 9)
  - Denmark (Folder 32: 10)
  - Dominican Republic
    - General (Folder 32: 11)
    - U.S. intervention, 1965 (Folder 32: 12)
    - Protests (Folder 32: 13)
    - Individuals (Folder 32: 14)
  - East Timor
    - General and maps (Folder 32: 15)
    - Independence struggle (Folder 32: 16)
    - Individuals (Folder 32: 17)
  - Egypt
    - General (Folder 32: 18)
    - Historical background (Folder 32: 19)
    - Wars, 1967 and 1973 (Folder 32: 20)
    - Individuals (Folder 32: 21)
  - El Salvador
    - Maps (Folder 32: 22)
    - General (Folder 32: 23-24)
    - Cristiani Burkard, Alfredo Felix (Folder 32: 25)
    - Junta troops (Folder 32: 26)
    - Repression and atrocities (Folder 32: 27)
    - Refugees (Folder 32: 28)
    - Demonstrations (Folder 32: 29)
    - Labor meetings and individuals (Folder 32: 30)
    - Guerrillas (Folder 32: 31)
    - Frente Farabundo Marti para la Liberacion Nacional (Folder 32: 32)
    - Communist youth conference, 1993 (Folder 32: 33)
    - Sao Paulo Forum, 1996 (Folder 32: 34)
  - Ethiopia—Demonstrations (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - Fiji (Folder 33: 2)
  - Finland (Folder 33: 3)
  - France
    - Historical background (Folder 33: 4)
    - Military (Folder 33: 5)
    - Protests, strikes and labor
      - 1968 May (Folder 33: 6)
      - 1980s and 1990s (Folder 33: 7-8)
      - Pacific nuclear testing, 1995 (Folder 33: 9)
    - World Federation of Democratic Youth and Communist Party meetings, Paris, 1993 (Folder 33: 10)
    - Gaulle, Charles de (Folder 33: 11)
    - Politicians (Folder 33: 12)
    - Socialist Party leaders (Folder 33: 13)
    - Fourth Internationalists (Folder 33: 14-15)
  - Georgia (Folder 33: 16)
  - Germany
    - Historical background (Folder 33: 17)
    - 19th century individuals (Folder 33: 18)
    - Bebel, August; Kautsky, Karl; Bernstein, Eduard (Folder 33: 19)
    - Liebknecht, Karl (Folder 33: 20)
    - Luxemburg, Rosa (Folder 33: 21)
    - Zetkin, Clara (Folder 33: 22)
    - Revolutionaries, 1918-1923 (Folder 33: 23)
    - Hitler, Adolf (Folder 33: 24)
    - Rise of Nazis (Folder 33: 25)
    - Nazi period (Folder 33: 26)
    - East (Folder 33: 27)
    - West
      - General (Folder 33: 28)
      - Anti-Vietnam War protests (Folder 33: 29)
      - Demonstrations, 1980s (Folder 33: 30)
      - Individuals (Folder 33: 31)
    - General, 1990s (Folder 33: 32)
    - Defense of immigrants, 1990s (Folder 33: 33)
    - Labor, 1990s (Folder 33: 34)
    - Military, 1990s (Folder 33: 35)
  - Ghana
    - General (Folder 33: 36)
    - Individuals (Folder 33: 37)
  - Great Britain
    - General (Folder 33: 38)
    - Historical background (Folder 33: 39)
    - Industry and agriculture (Folder 33: 40)
    - Strikes (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - Miners
      - General (Folder 34: 2)
      - Strike, 1984-1985 (Folder 34: 3)
    - Immigration and anti-racist protests (Folder 34: 4)
    - Miscellaneous protests (Folder 34: 5)
    - Thatcher, Margaret (Folder 34: 6)
    - Conservative Party leaders (Folder 34: 7)
    - Labour Party leaders and unionists (Folder 34: 8)
    - Scargill, Arthur (Folder 34: 9)
    - Healy, Gerry (Folder 34: 10)
    - Leftists (Folder 34: 11)
    - Fourth Internationalists (Folder 34: 12)
    - Miscellaneous individuals (Folder 34: 13)
  - Greece
    - General (Folder 34: 14)
    - Civil War (Folder 34: 15)
    - Protests (Folder 34: 16)
  - Grenada
    - General (Folder 34: 17-19)
    - Bishop, Maurice (Folder 34: 20)
    - Mass demonstrations (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - Revolutionary troops (Folder 35: 2)
    - Agriculture and other economic activities (Folder 35: 3)
    - Individuals (Folder 35: 4)
  - Guatemala
    - General (Folder 35: 5)
    - Struggles (Folder 35: 6)
    - Cerezo, Vinicio (Folder 35: 7)
    - Individuals (Folder 35: 8)
  - Guinea—Individuals (Folder 35: 9)
  - Guinea-Bissau
    - War for independence (Folder 35: 10)
    - Cabral, Amilcar (Folder 35: 11)
  - Guyana—Individuals (Folder 35: 12)
  - Haiti
    - General (Folder 35: 13)
    - Historical background (Folder 35: 14)
    - Demonstrations, post-Duvalier period (Folder 35: 15-16)
    - Individuals (Folder 35: 17)
  - Honduras (Folder 35: 18)
  - Hungary (Folder 35: 19)
  - Iceland (Folder 35: 20)
  - India
    - General (Folder 35: 21)
    - Protests (Folder 35: 22)
    - Asian Students Association Conference, New Delhi, 1992 (Folder 35: 23)
    - Individuals (Folder 35: 24)
  - Indonesia
    - General (Folder 35: 25)
    - Struggle for independence (Folder 35: 26)
    - Protests (Folder 35: 27)
  - Iran
    - Historical background (Folder 35: 28)
    - Mohammed Reza Pahlavi, Shah (Folder 35: 29)
    - Repression, pre-1979 (Folder 35: 30)
    - Revolution, 1979 (Folder 35: 31)
    - U.S. Embassy seizure, 1979 (Folder 35: 32)
    - General, post-1979 period (Folder 35: 33)
    - Troops, post-1979 (Folder 35: 34)
    - Repression and protests, post-1979 (Folder 35: 35)
    - Women, post-1979 (Folder 35: 36)
    - Iran-Iraq War (Folder 35: 37)
    - Khomeini, Ruhollah (Folder 35: 38)
    - Islamic Republic leaders (Folder 35: 39)
    - Opposition leaders (non-socialist) (Folder 35: 40)
    - Baraheni, Reza (Folder 35: 41)
    - Fourth Internationalists (Folder 35: 42)
    - Kurdistan (Box-folder 36: 1)
    - Miscellany (Folder 36: 2)
  - Iraq
    - Gulf War, 1991 (Folder 36: 3)
    - Kurds, 1991 (Folder 36: 4)
    - Revolts, 1991 (Folder 36: 5)
    - Individuals (Folder 36: 6)
  - Ireland
    (including Northern Ireland)
    - General (Folder 36: 7)
    - Historical background (Folder 36: 8)
    - British troops (Folder 36: 9)
    - Individuals (Folder 36: 10)
  - Israel
    (including Palestine and Palestinians)
    - Historical background (Folder 36: 11)
    - Mass protests (Folder 36: 12)
    - Prisons (Folder 36: 13)
    - Settlements and housing (Folder 36: 14)
    - Social conditions (Folder 36: 15)
    - Gaza (Folder 36: 16)
    - West Bank (Folder 36: 17)
    - Prime ministers (Folder 36: 18)
    - Arafat, Yasser (Folder 36: 19)
    - Palestinian leaders (Folder 36: 20)
    - Palestinians (Folder 36: 21-22)
    - Fourth Internationalists (Michel Warschawsky) (Folder 36: 23)
    - Individuals (Folder 36: 24)
  - Italy
    - Historical background (Folder 36: 25)
    - Protests (Folder 36: 26)
    - Gramsci, Antonio (Folder 36: 27)
    - Individuals (Folder 36: 28)
  - Jamaica
    - General (Folder 36: 29)
    - Protests and repression (Folder 36: 30)
    - Individuals (Folder 36: 31)
  - Japan (Box 37)
    - General (Folder 37: 1)
    - Workers and industry (Folder 37: 2)
    - Minorities (Folder 37: 3)
    - Farmers' protests (Narita Airport) (Folder 37: 4)
    - Student protests (Folder 37: 5)
    - Protests re Korea and Philippines (Folder 37: 6)
    - Anti-U.S. protests (Folder 37: 7)
    - Anti-nuclear protests (Folder 37: 8)
    - Atom bombs (Hiroshima and Nagasaki) (Folder 37: 9)
    - Fourth Internationalists (Folder 37: 10)
    - Individuals (Folder 37: 11)
  - Jordan
    - Maps (Folder 37: 12)
    - General (Folder 37: 13)
    - Palestinian refugees (Folder 37: 14)
    - U.S. forces (Folder 37: 15)
    - Hussein, King (Folder 37: 16)
  - Kazakhstan—Maps (Folder 37: 17)
  - Kenya
    - United Nations Women's Conference, Nairobi, 1985 (Folder 37: 18)
    - Individuals (Folder 37: 19)
  - Korea
    - North
      - General (Folder 37: 20)
      - Militant reporting trip, 1998 (Folder 37: 21)
      - Victorious Fatherland Liberation War Museum, Pyongyang—Booklet (Folder 37: 22)
      - Kim Il Sung and cult (Folder 37: 23)
      - Individuals (Folder 37: 24)
    - South
      - General (Folder 37: 25)
      - Korean War (Folder 37: 26)
      - Armed forces (Folder 37: 27)
      - Government officials (Folder 37: 28)
      - Anti-government activists (Folder 37: 29)
  - Kuwait (Folder 37: 30)
  - Laos